Jerry Li

+14343104701 / jerrysmailbox77@gmail.com / linkedin.com/in/jiangyuan-li-051095327 / github.com/jerrylovescheese

A first-year student at the University of Virginia, Jerry's interest in computers stemmed from his first encounter with a computer at 5 years old, where he was mesmerized by the buttons, toggles, sliders, and other components of a window. That interest led to further exploration of the logic behind every object and interface and fundamentally, how a computer interacts with humans. Jerry's interest in UX and web design reignited in 2022 when he built the wiki for his high school team in the International Genetically Engineered Machine contest. After self-learning HTML and CSS, Jerry's obsession with the web grew exponentially as he started his website and later his blog at https://jerryly.top. Starting in 11th grade, to prepare himself with sufficient tools and skills in software development, Jerry has actively taken courses in Computer Science and performed well in classes like Data Structures & Algorithms I and Computer Systems & Organizations I. He has also learned JavaScript and is currently learning React.

Education

University of Virginia

Charlottesville, VA

Bachelor of Arts in Computer Science

August 2024 - Present

Relevant coursework: Applied Linear Algebra (ongoing), Data Structures & Algorithms I (A), Computer Systems & Organization I (ongoing)

Second High School attached to Beijing Normal University

Honor Roll Student, Cumulative GPA: 4.6/4.0

Beijing, China August 2021 - June 2024

Experience

iGEM Competition Web Design Group Leader

March 2022 - November 2022

Second High School attached to Beijing Normal University

Beijing, China

- · Self-taught HTML and CSS in a month, developed a prototype of website layout within days
- Integrated Frozen-Flask Python packages to adapt to the iGEM repository structure
- Refined the layout and polished the contents of the site

Web Designer and Developer

October 2022 - Present

Personal Website https://jerryly.top

- Under the VS Code IDE, utilized HTML to create content, CSS to design the appearance, and JavaScript to build "welcome" and "countdown" pages and common layout injection
- · Optimized performance and user experience with responsive design and interactive elements
- Continued exploration into the backend with a separate blog subdomain powered by Flask

Graphic Design Enthusiast

2019 - Present

Gallery of works available at https://jerryly.top/gallery

- Using tools like Figma, Sketch, Photoshop and Illustrator, designed numerous posters, infographics and user interfaces for high school major events and publications
- Progression to 3D designs with Blender enabled me to utilize glass and shading to create intriguing visuals for the posters and advertise my design

Projects

Interactive blog system

February 2023 - Present

An extension on my current web project

- · Building a blog system where anyone can post anything with the help of SQL
- Learning React to make my website reduce lines of code and improve responsiveness

Honors and Awards

International Genetically Engineered Machine (iGEM)

March 2022 - November 2022

Gold Medal; Top 10 Global High School Team; Best Presentation; Best Wiki

High School Mathematical Contest in Modeling (HiMCM)

November 2022 - May 2023

Sep 2021 – Feb 2022

Honorable Mention

China Thinks Big (CTB)

Grand Finals Fast Track Qualifiers and Regional First

Skills

Programming Languages

Python, Java, HTML/CSS, C

Frameworks and Libraries Flask, React

Developer Tools

Git/GitHub/GitLab, Stack Overflow

Artificial Intelligence Tools Claude, GitHub Copilot

Languages

Chinese (Mandarin), English, French